# Jeremy Barnes

**Software Engineer** 

jeremy.w.barnes@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/jeremywbarnes
+1 (818) 203-1393

Studio City, CA

### About\_

Software engineer with bachelor's degree in computer science and 4 years of experience in software development. Currently developing a full stack TypeScript/React/AWS cloud application that implements video encoding and delivery. Looking for a mid-level software development role on a team of highly driven engineers to learn, create and problemsolve in a collaborative environment. A self-reliant, curious engineer who strives to leave code better than it was found.

### Skills\_

Programming TypeScript, JavaScript, C#, Java, SQL, PowerShell, Windows Batch, Visual Studio Code, Git, Jira

Frontend React, React Hooks, jQuery, Electron.js, HTML5, CSS, Fluent UI, Bootstrap

**Backend** Node.js, AWS, Heroku, Express.js, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Elasticsearch, Firebase, MySQL, SQL Server

## **Work Experience**

Software Engineer | Spafax | Hollywood, CA / Remote

August 2018 - Present

- Collaborated remotely to design, code and deploy backend microservices and user-centered frontend pages for video ingestion, transcoding and delivery from the cloud using TypeScript/React/AWS.
- Researched AWS offerings and developed a prototype application to persuade senior management to migrate onpremise video production to the cloud, improving scalability and reliability.
- Coordinated with music team and developed a desktop application that implements a fully automated audio encoding and delivery pipeline, reducing the overhead cost of 2 employees.
- Coded advanced fuzzy search algorithms to match employee-scheduled music content with 2 million unique audio source files, achieving a long-term accuracy rate of 99.7%.
- Eliminated critical production bottleneck by liaising with content ingestion team and developing software to automate large file movement 300% faster to the on-premise production network.
- Leveraged knowledge in TypeScript, JavaScript, C#, PowerShell, Node.js, React, jQuery, AWS, MongoDB, Git, Jira

Systems Engineer | Spafax | Hollywood, CA

January 2014 – July 2018

- Redesigned and relocated datacenter to increase video file delivery from 300 to 6000 files per month though widespread network, storage and encoding optimizations.
- Transitioned legacy tape-based video workflows to fully digital workflows with 100% MPAA security compliance significantly improving delivery time.
- Directed and mentored a junior team member throughout several projects related to the support of day-to-day IT operations for 2 internal networks, 60 servers, and 100 workstations.
- Leveraged knowledge in TCP/IP, VLAN, firewall security, SANs, 10GE/fiber, H.265 encoding, Windows Server, AD

Software Application Support Engineer | Spafax | Orange, CA

July 2011 - December 2013

Software Engineer | DataPath | San Diego, CA

November 2006 - June 2008

#### **Education** \_

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development | UCLA Extension | Westwood, CA

June 2019 – November 2019

4.0 GPA, Top of class

 $\textbf{Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science} \ | \ \textbf{Bucknell University} \ | \ \textbf{Lewisburg, PA}$